你母亲的遗愿是让你戴上她的戒指
Your mother's last wish was for you to wear her ring.
爸爸呢？
Where's daddy?
沃因，你还活着吗？
Voyin, you're alive?
你敬爱的探长救了我的命
Your beloved inspector saved my life.
那枚戒指是来自维也纳合伙人的礼物吗？
Was that ring a gift from the silent partner from Vienna?
不要相信他们
Don't trust them.
千万不要相信他们
Don't you ever trust them.
不要相信他们
Do not trust them.
你什么时候回来？
When are you coming back?
我很快就回来
I won't be long.
你有什么消息要告诉我吗？
Do you have any news for me?
看来年轻的索罗金已经完成了他的使命
Looks like young Sorokin has done his part.
将军已经被处理掉了
General has been disposed of.
真的吗? 这不用你告诉我
Really? I don't need you to tell me that.
就这些吗？
Is that all?
那个警察又来了，长官
That cop came by again. The captain.
他想怎么样？
What does he want now?
他说矛在他身上
He says he could deliver the spear.
这样吗？
Is that so?
继续跟进
Check it out.
亲爱的上帝…
Dear Lord…
可怜可怜我吧
Have mercy on me.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第一季 第九集
BLACK SUN EPISODE 9
你真是个好榜样，不是吗？
You're a real role-model, aren't you?
他整晚都在喝酒
He spent the whole night drinking.
请给他来一杯双份咖啡
A double coffee for him, please.
你是普莱蒂科西奇督察吗？
Inspector Pletikosich?
我才是问问题的人
I'm the one asking questions.
节哀
I'm sorry.
至少你没白杀那个混蛋
At least you didn't kill that bastard for nothing.
在我们抓到那个狗娘养的幕后黑手之前我不会罢休
I won't stop till we get the son of a bitch who's in charge.
我想你可能错了
I think you might be wrong.
国王可能是疯了
The Prince may well be mad,
但是和德国人合作...绝不可能
but to work with the Germans... That can't be. No way.
阿夫拉姆就是这样
Avram was like that.
一会儿像个疯子，一会儿又清醒过来
One moment he was mad, the next perfectly lucid.
然而，他们都画了黑色太阳
Yet both have painted the Black Sun.
好吧
Alright.
那么你去托普尼卡精神病院审问他
Then go to Toponica Asylum and question him.
我朋友的儿子在那里工作
My friend's son works there.
他会带你进去的
He'll get you in.
你不和我一起去吗？
Aren't you coming with me?
我想我知道修道士是谁了
I think I've found the Monk.
我得去看看
I'm going to check it out.
- 小心点 - 别担心
- Be careful. - Don't worry.
在这儿等会，清醒一下
Wait here and sober up.
我会派人来接你
I'll send a man to pick you up.
- 普尔莎，我的朋友，再见 - 再见，我的朋友
- Prsho, my friend, bye-bye. - Farewell, my friend.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 难熬的一晚? - 和往常一样
- Tough night, huh? - As usual.
我忘了告诉你，警察在找你
I forgot to tell you that police were looking for you.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Were they? - Yes.
逮捕阿夫拉姆的督察昨天来过
Inspector who arrested Avram, he came by yesterday.
他可能需要我的专业意见？
He probably needed my expert opinion on something?
康斯坦丁？
Constantine?
我们结婚多久了？六年？
How long have we been married? Six years?
对你来说也许不是那么长，但这是我生命的五分之一
It may not be that long for you, but it's one fifth of my life.
我了解你
And I know you.
我很了解你，知道你什么时候不对劲
I know you well enough to see when something's wrong.
我爱你，尽管我们很疯狂
I love you despite all our madness.
并且虽然你不是我的唯一
And though you're not my only one,
我也绝不会让你受一点伤害
I won't let anything happen to you.
亲爱的，我也不想伤害你
Darling, I wouldn't wish any harm on you either.
但伤害已经发生了
It already happened.
发生了什么？
What happened?
- 你在隐瞒什么？告诉我 - 我有什么好隐瞒的！
- What are you hiding, tell me?! - What do I have to hide?!
告诉我实话，你晚上去哪里？
Just tell me the truth. Where do you go in the evenings?
你在干什么? 为什么你的衬衫上总是有血迹？
What are you up to? Why are your shirts often blood-stained?
我和病人一起工作
I work with patients.
他们中的一些人深受病魔困扰而且具有攻击性
Some of them are deeply disturbed and can be aggressive.
那这是什么? ！
What is this?!
你从哪儿弄来的？
Where did you get that?
- 这是什么? ! - 还给我
- What is this?! - Give it back.
这是什么，康斯坦丁！
What is this, Constantine?!
你在舞会上都不会戴面具，但是看看这个！
You wouldn't wear a mask at the ball, and look at this here!
- 还给我 - 你晚上戴着这个
- Give it back. - You wear these at night
然后用拉丁语低语
and you murmur something in Latin.
当我在黑暗中看到你，我浑身发冷
When I see you in the dark, I get chills down my spine.
克里斯塔
Krista.
我会解释的
I'll explain everything.
我会解释一切，但今天不行
I'll explain everything, but not today.
- 现在就告诉我 - 现在不是时候，我会..
- Tell me now. - It's not a good time. I will...
- 现在就告诉我! - 我会给你个解释
- Tell me now! - I'll explain everything,
等时机成熟的时候
when the time comes.
卡塔，把我的外套拿来！
Kata, bring me my coat!
- 你要去哪里? - 我会让你好奇..
- Where are you going? - I'll let you wonder...
就像你让我想知道你晚上都在哪里一样
Just like how you leave me wondering where you spend your nights.
等等，冷静点
Wait. Hold on... Calm down...
我会告诉你一切，但你现在不能走
I'll tell you everything, but you can't leave now?
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
我现在不能跟你解释! 你明白吗？
I can't do it now! Do you understand?
- 我要走了 - 不，如果你现在离开…
- I'm leaving. - No, no. If you leave now...
- 康斯坦丁，放开我 - 如果你现在离开，那就完了
- Constantine, let me go. - If you leave now, that's it.
我什么都做不了
I won't be able to help.
- 让我走，康斯坦丁! - 我帮不了你
- Let me go, Constantine! - I won't be able to help you.
我再也不想见到你了
I don't ever want to see you again.
我妻子刚走
My wife, she just left.
把她活着带回来
Bring her back, alive.
- 你好 - 寄信还是电报？
- Hello. - A letter or a telegram?
如果你没有饼干，那我就发电报好了
If you don't have any cookies, I'll take the telegram.
内容？
Yes?
给顾客量尺寸; 去拿衣服; 不会太久
Customer's measurements taken; off to get the suit; won't be long.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你把这位小姐照顾得很好
You took good care of the young lady.
我能怎么办？
What was I to do?
你让我好好照顾她
You told me to look after her while you were inside.
你听说朱基奇失踪了吗？
Did you hear that Djukich has disappeared?
全镇的人都在找他
The whole town is looking for him.
是的，但我没听说有女士失踪
Yes, but I haven't heard about a missing lady.
你是唯一一个在找她的人
And you're the only one looking for her.
你恋爱了吗？
Did you fall in love?
现在都结束了
Eh... It's over now.
恋爱中的男孩
Lover boy.
Tell me, what's the name of that cop who saved your damsel back then?
塔纳西耶维奇？
Tanasiyevich?
你知道他住哪儿吗? 带我去
Do you know where he lives? Take me there.
著名的塔纳西耶维奇督察，见到你是我的荣幸
The famous Inspector Tanasiyevich. It is my honour.
我不知道我这么有名
I didn't know I was so famous.
对于普通大众可能不出名
Maybe not among the general public,
但是对于那些知道的人来说你绝对是
but for those in the know, you definitely are. Please...
我可以问一下，你来这里是为了私事还是为了逮捕我？
May I ask, are you here on a private matter or to arrest me?
我会说一些介于两者之间的话
I would say something in between.
介于私人拜访和逮捕之间的事？
Something between a private visit and the arrest?
是的
Yes.
确实很有意思，您说…
Interesting, indeed. Go on...
我想你已经听说监狱的谋杀案了吧？
I suppose you've heard about the murders in Koshutnyak?
太可怕了，几十具尸体
Horrible. Scores of dead bodies.
包括州检察官
Including the state prosecutor.
朱基奇先生被谋杀了？我以为他是失踪了
Mr. Djukich was murdered? I thought he was missing.
我们有理由怀疑他是被谋杀了
We have a reason to suspect he was murdered.
天啊，塔纳西耶维奇，别这样，虽然我跟他不熟
Jesus, Tanasiyevich, don't do this. I didn't know him well,
但你无权宣布他死亡
but you have no right to pronounce him dead.
有意思
Interesting.
你觉得他还活着，但你却用过去式说认识他
You think he's alive and yet you said you knew him
好像他已经死了一样
not that you know him.
你听起来像个推理小说中的侦探
You sound like a mystery novel detective.
怀疑朱基奇先生是被谋杀的
Just as it is suspected that Mr. Djukich was murdered,
是因为据说他死前在科舒特尼亚克的一座别墅里
it is also believed that a meeting in a villa in Koshutnyak,
应该和你有个会面，米里奇先生
was supposed to be with you, Mr. Mirich.
你怀疑这个，怀疑那个…一个接一个的怀疑…
You suspect this, suspect that... Suspicion after suspicion...
你到底是哲学家还是督察？
Suspicion is... Are you a philosopher or an inspector?
你知道那幢别墅的主人是谁吗？
Do you by any chance know who owns that villa?
我想你在怀疑是我干的？
I suppose you're suspecting it's me?
我们怀疑这栋别墅的主人是个修道士
We're suspecting that the villa is owned by a Monk.
现在你又把教堂牵扯进来了？
Now you're implicating the church?
我们还怀疑…
And we also suspect that...
那个修道士就是你…
the Monk in question is you...
米里奇先生
Mr. Mirich.
现在唯一的问题就是，修道士是否就是斩首者
The only question now is whether he's the beheader.
塔纳西耶维奇督察…
Mr. Tanasiyevich...
我不信教
I'm not a religious man,
但我尊重教会和神职人员
but I respect the Church and clergy,
尤其是修道士
especially monks.
我相信他们可以做任何事情
I believe they can do all sorts of things,
但他们不会到处砍别人的头
but they don't go around severing people's heads.
也许吧
Maybe.
也许这就是你在法庭上的辩护词
Maybe that'll be the defence line at your trial
塔纳西耶维奇督察
Mr. Tanasiyevich,
你知道巴尔干半岛最大的麻烦是什么吗？
do you know what is the Balkans' greatest trouble?
不知道，但我真的很想知道
No. But I'd really like to find out.
就是像你这样有头脑的人
It's that the people like you, who were blessed with brains,
和那些社会底层卑鄙的人渣没什么两样
behave no better than the lowlife scum.
作为一个典型的巴尔干人，我不介意没礼貌
Being a typical Balkan man, I don't mind the lack of manners.
我不会因为一个酗酒的警察把精英们当酒肉朋友
I'm not crossed that a boozing copper thinks it's fine
而感到离谱
to talk to the elite as they were drinking buddies.
不，我觉得很有趣
No, I find it amusing.
但是，考虑到我是一个
But, considering that I'm a man
想要把这个一潭死水的地方，变成现代国家
who wants to turn this backwater into a modern state,
我需要抑制我内心和外来的冲动
I need to subdue that urge in and around me.
那么，你也想抑制我咯？
So, you'd like to subdue me too?
不
No.
我只是想提醒你，你待得太久了
I'd just like to remind you that you've overstayed your welcome.
下次见，米里奇先生
Till next time, Mr. Mirich.
我认为不会有下次了
I don't think there is going to be a next time.
也许我们会在教堂见面
Maybe we'll see each other at the church.
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
我知道你喜欢花
Here, I know you liked flowers.
你听不到我说话，而且这些话你可能已经听烦了
You can't hear me, and it's probably all the same to you,
但是对你的孩子来说并不都一样
but it's not all the same to your child.
我们把孩子带到这世界上，让他看到有人会…
We'll bring him here so he can see that someone...
关心并且爱他的妈妈，你明白吗？
loved and cared for his mom. Do you understand?
拜托，别在墓地从背后拍我
Oh, please, don't do that at the cemetery.
对不起
Sorry.
你真善良
This is really nice of you.
这就是你的套路！
So that's how you want to play it!
我找来了保镖，你却想自己解决问题
I get the bodyguards, and you take the matter into your own hands.
如果我依靠他们，我就和可怜的沃因一样了
If I relied on them, I'd be sharing the fate of poor Voyin.
这么说不公平
You're not fair.
我对他的安全没有责任
I wasn't responsible for his safety.
而且我知道至少有两伙人在暗中保护你
And I knew there were at least two parties looking after you.
安静
Quiet.
你怎么知道的？
How could you know that?
像你这样的美人一定会很有安全感
A beauty like you is bound to feel safe.
谁会伤害这么漂亮的女士呢？
Who would harm such a pretty lady?
你能不能先不要讲你的波斯尼亚冷笑话了？
Can you quit your Bosnian charm for a bit?
不，不... 这是黑塞哥维那的冷笑话
No, no... It's Herzegovina charm.
停下，塔尼！这是我的朋友！
Stop, Tane! That's my friend!
是安全的！
It is safe!
塔纳西耶维奇上尉？
Captain Tanasiyevich?
第一团三营
Third battalion, First regiment.
他像抓小鸡崽一样抓住了我的人
He caught my guy like a chicken.
好了，出去
C'mon, get out.
- 戈卢比奇 - 该死！
- Golubich. - Damn!
你还说很安全
You say it's safe,
巴尔干半岛最危险的人就在我们家
and the Balkans' most dangerous man is at our house.
当最危险的人站在你这边的时候，不会变得更安全
It doesn't get any safer when the most dangerous is on your side.
你站在我这边吗，中士？
Are you on my side, sergeant?
达维多维奇小姐是一个朋友的朋友
Miss Davidovich is a friend of a friend.
我听说你背叛了你的主人
I heard you turned against your masters,
这让我们比以前更亲密了
which makes the two us much closer than before.
戈卢比奇同志
Comrade Golubich,
我看得出来你已经让自己很舒服了
I can see you've already made yourself comfortable.
好像这是你自己家
Keep feeling like at home.
唯一的问题是…
The only thing is...
你和那些白人叛徒交上了朋友
you made friends with those white traitors.
不管是谁，只要是站在沃兰赫尔那边的人，都不可能是我的朋友
Whoever sided with Vrangel's killers can hardly be my friend.
戈卢比奇，你敌人的人比我还多
Golubich, the people you hate more than me,
与黑帮和一些古怪的德国人合作
have teamed up with gangsters and some freaky Germans.
唯一愿意跟我合作的只有沃兰赫尔的俄国人
The only ones willing to fight are Vrangel's Russians.
他们只是想要找回被偷走的东西
They simply want something that's been stolen from them.
那么，我应该和谁合作呢
So, whom should I team up with
去找那些砍头的混蛋吗？
to get those head-chopping bastards?
我的伙伴独自一人在外面
My fellow is all alone outside.
也许这位小姐可以去陪陪他
Maybe young lady could keep him company.
没必要嫉妒
No need to be jealous!
反正你也没那么有魅力
You're not that interesting anyway.
- 马诺伊洛 - 怎么了？
- Manoylo! - What is it?
- 你就是我的保镖? - 我是个屁保镖…
- Are you my bodyguard? - Some bodyguard I am...
- 普莱蒂科西奇督察是哪位? - 斯坦科? 他就是
- Inspector Pletikosich? - Stanko? There.
普莱蒂科西奇督察？
Inspector Pletikosich?
- 是的 - 我是斯坦诺耶维奇
- Yes. - Stanoyevich.
塔纳西耶维奇督察派我来的
Inspector Tanasiyevich sent me.
我要带你去托普尼卡，我们要尽快出发
I'm taking you to Toponica. You don't have much time.
- 我们什么时候出发? - 现在
- When do we leave? - Right away.
沃兰赫尔的人在找什么？
What is it that Vrangel's people are looking for?
你应该比我更清楚
You should know that better than me.
更不用说可能就是你偷走的
Not to mention that it was probably you who stole it.
塔纳西耶维奇，别玩游戏了！
Tanasiyevich, let's quite the games!
把那把长矛给我，我好把它还给俄国人
Give me that lance so I can return it to Russia where it belongs.
作为回报，我会把那个染指每一个肮脏阴谋的
In return I am going to serve you the head of the scumbag
混蛋尸体交给你
who has got his fingers in every dirty scheme.
- 修道士? - 是的
- The Monk? - The Monk.
可我不能交出长矛
Well, I can't get the lance...
除非我先抓住那个修道士
unless I first get the Monk.
上尉，如果我想杀你的话，我随时都可以动手
Captain, as easily as I could kill you if I wanted to,
我可以不帮你的忙直接拿到长矛
I could take the lance without doing you any favours.
但是我对战友有感情
But I get sentimental to a fellow soldier.
我也不喜欢你想除掉的那个混蛋…
And I'm not fond of that scumbag you want to get rid of...
但别考验我的耐心，兄弟
But don't test my patience, bro.
好吧，中士
Fair enough, sergeant.
但我肯定你不认为我会把它放在这个房子里？
But I'm sure you don't think I have it here, in the house?
我觉得你就放在这里
I somehow think you do.
但是，假设我相信你
But let's say I believe you.
就像1914年一样，是时候联合起来对抗德国佬了
Just like in 1914, it is time to go against the Krauts together,
一旦我们联起手来
And once we corner them...
对他们来说就是地狱
there will be hell.
可不是吗
You could put it like that...
我会告诉你交货的时间和地点
I'll let you know the time and place for the exchange.
- 你觉得可以吗? - 可以，中士
- Does that work for you? - It does, sergeant.
- 好的，长官 - 再见，穆斯塔法
- Okay, captain. - Cheers, Mustapha.
小伙子，给这位女士留点空间
Lad, give the lady some space.
你要咖啡还是茶？
Would you like a coffee or tea?
不用了，谢谢
No, thanks.
你确定玛雅今天不来吗？
Are you sure Maya won't be coming today?
是的，她昨天有一个重要的会议
Yes. She had an important meeting yesterday.
她和朱基奇先生一起离开了
She left with Mr. Djukich.
不好意思,
Excuse me,
你有镇静剂吗？
do you have any tranquillising drops?
是的，我会带来的
Yes. I'll bring them.
阿瓦库莫维奇夫人？
Mrs. Avakumovich?
帕帕哈吉，抱歉打扰了
Papahagi, I'm sorry to intrude.
玛雅不在，我不知道该怎么办
Maya is not here, and I don't know what to do.
回家吧，阿瓦库莫维奇夫人
Go home, Mrs. Avakumovich.
无论是什么在折磨你脆弱的灵魂
Whatever is tormenting your delicate soul,
好好睡一觉，你会感觉好点的
you'll feel better after a good night's sleep.
我保证我会告诉玛雅你在找她
I promise I'll tell Maya you were looking for her,
她会尽快来看你的
and she'll visit you as soon as possible.
- 好的 - 好的
- All right. - Yes.
需要我们的司机送你回家吗？
Do you want our chauffeur to drive you home?
不用了，谢谢
No, thanks.
谢谢你的好话
But thank you for your kind words.
有你照顾玛雅，她真的很幸运
Maya is very lucky to have you.
天呐…
Dear God...
你们银行的盾徽上也有同样的铭文
The same inscription is on your bank's coat of arms.
"图勒"和你父亲一起建立了银行
Thule Society founded the bank with your father,
现在他们因为这个到处砍头
and now they are severing people's heads because of this.
你知道这一切却不告诉我？
You knew about all this and didn't tell me?
就像你没告诉我将军的照片一样
Just like how you didn't tell me about general's photos.
我还没找到机会告诉你
I didn't get a chance to tell you, and you won't.
塔尼，那些照片和这件事没有关系
Tane, those pictures have nothing to do with this.
我只是想要回我的银行
I'm just trying to get my bank back.
但我现在才意识到我的对手是谁
But I've only now realised whom I'm up against.
阿里比耶 · 米里奇... 他也是"图勒"的人吗？
Alimpiye Mirich... Is he a Thule?
他是个罪犯，不是"图勒"的人
He's a criminal, but not a Thule.
谁把你介绍给他的？
Who introduced you to him?
帕帕哈吉
Papahagi.
好吧
Alright.
这是你第一次听说吗？
And this is the first time you heard about it?
塔尼…
Tane...
好吧
Right.
还有其他需要公开的秘密吗？
Are there any other secrets that need to be disclosed?
为什么要锁门？
Why is it locked?
太好了，真是太好了！
Great, just great!
你说过你会等我的
You said you'd wait for me.
是的
I did.
然后呢？
And?
你这个可怜虫…
You wretch...
你做了个错误的选择
you've made a bad choice.
你也不用再等我了
And you don't have to wait for me any longer.
我们确实开了个好头！
We really are off to a good start!
秘密自己就公开了
Secrets are revealing themselves.
再见，督察
Goodbye, inspector.
卧槽，这是什么？
Holy fuck, what is this?
我在找一个男孩
I'm looking for a boy.
现在这个还不够吗？
The one you got is not enough?
要找一个孩子，他出生时就被人从母亲身边带走了
This one is a child. He was taken from mother at birth.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Was he? - Yes.
他现在在哪儿？
And where is he now?
在娜塔莉女王的孤儿院，但我不知道怎么确认他的身份
In Queen Natalie's orphanage, but I don't know how to ID him.
这个男孩没有证件，母亲也没有登记他的出生证明
The boy has no documents, mother never registered his birth.
- 也许他们改了他的名字 - 终于有你不知道的事了！
- Maybe they changed his name. - Finally, something you don't know!
哦，但是我知道！
Oh, but I do!
我知道他入院的日期
I know the date when he was admitted,
我知道出生日期
and I know the date of birth.
但是那个星期有五个男孩出生
But they had five boys that week.
好吧，去那里挑一个最可爱的
Well, just go there and pick the cutest one.
这不是开玩笑
This is not a joke.
他是斯坦科被杀的朋友的孩子
He's the kid of Stanko's murdered friend.
天哪，博雅纳! 你是医生还是督察？
Jesus, Boyana! Are you a doctor or an inspector?
孩子母亲的尸检做完了吗？
Have you done the autopsy on the mother?
报告出来了吗？
Do you have the report?
你在尸体上有没有找到任何标记？
Have you listed any marks on the body?
这是报告
Here's the report.
眼睛的颜色，头发，胎记，脚的形状
Colour of eyes, hair, birthmarks, shape of the feet.
看…
See...
看着母亲，找到儿子
Look at the mother, find the son.
就是这样，过来
That's it! Come here.
求你了，不要，你对我来说太老了
Please, don't. You're too old for me.
嗨，你太老了，巴比奇
Ah, Babich, it's too late...
最近的谋杀案还是没有好消息…
Still no good news about recent murders...
警方正在寻找绑架国家检察官的嫌疑人
Police are looking for suspects in abduction of State Prosecutor,
沃因 · 朱基奇先生解除了保镖的武装
Mr. Voyin Djukich, and disarmed his bodyguards.
凶手！
Murderer!
杀人犯！
Murderer! Murderer!
- 等等，我求你了 - 你在求什么？
- Hold on, I beg of you. - What are you begging for?
听我说完
To hear me out.
警察会听你说的，你这个混蛋！
Police will hear you out, you bastard!
如果只有我的生命命悬一线
If it was only my life that's hanging by a thread,
我不会拦着你报警
I'd tell you to call them...
报警吧
Call them.
你做这些都是为了我？是吗？
You're doing all this for me? Are you?
我这么做是为了救你的命
I'm doing this to save your life.
这就是他们没杀我的原因吗！
Is that why they didn't kill me?!
如果你不相信我，就报警
If you don't believe me, call the police.
报警吧！
Do it!
这样
Here's the thing,
除非你马上告诉我，你知道的一切
unless you tell me everything you know right away,
那我就报警，我们都去面对现实
I'm calling the police and we both will face it.
明白了吗！
Is that clear?!
好的，但是我们必须去老房子
Yes, but we have to go to the old house.
穆斯塔法，你在吗？
Mustapha, are you there?
托波尼卡精神病院
TOPONICA, PSYCHIATRIC ASYLUM, SERBIA, SCS KINGDOM
请进
Hello?
- 不好意思 - 大声点，米哈伊尔
- Excuse me. - Speak up, Mihail.
殿下，有人要见您
Your Highness, someone is here to see you.
我没有预约
I have no appointments.
是没有经过预约的
This is unannounced.
警察局的一位先生想和你谈谈
A gentleman from the police wants to talk to you.
米哈伊尔
Mihail.
别担心，这不会花很长时间的
Do not worry, this won't take long.
下午好，殿下
Good afternoon, Your Excellency.
你是谁？
Who are you?
斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇，来自贝尔格莱德的技术警察
Stanko Pletikosich, Technical Police, Belgrade.
有证件吗？
Do you have an ID?
凶杀案和性犯罪督察
Homicide and Sex Crimes Inspector.
那么，一个性犯罪督察来这个被上帝遗弃的垃圾场做什么？
So, what's a sex inspector doing in this God forsaken dump?
我和我的同事塔纳西耶维奇正在处理一个案子
I am working on a case with my colleague, Tanasiyevich.
塔纳西耶维奇上尉？
Captain Tanasiyevich?
- 是的 - 那么…
- Yes. - So...
一个精神病国王怎么做才能…
How can a mad prince...
帮助到警察呢？
help the police?
贝尔格莱德发生了一连串离奇的谋杀案
We've had a string of bizarre murders in Belgrade.
那些被砍下的人头
Oh, this thing with the severed heads.
我听说过
I've heard about it.
你到底听说了什么？
And what exactly did you hear?
你在怀疑我吗，小伙子？
Are you questioning me, lad?
不，我只是觉得你的信息可能会帮我
No. I just think you might help me.
我真的很想知道该怎么做？
I'd really like to know how?
这是你画的？
You painted this?
是的，这是我疯狂思想的产物
Yes, it is the product of my deranged mind.
黑色太阳
The Black Sun.
就像凶手用他的血画的一样，对吧？
Just like the one killer drew with his blood, right?
所以你认为，如果精神病国王…
So you reckon, if the mad prince...
画出了同样的画
is painting the same images,
也许凶手是想夺朝篡位？
perhaps the killers want to install him on the throne?
然而你还不确定精神病国王
And yet you're not sure if the mad prince
是真的疯了，还是在装疯？
is really that crazy or is he just pretending?
是的，我就是这么想的
Yes, those are my exact thoughts.
听着，小伙子... 请坐
Listen, lad... Have a seat.
听着，孩子…
Listen, son...
如果乔尔杰·卡拉乔尔杰维奇真的想要夺权…
Had Djordje Karadjordjevich really wanted to grab the power...
砍掉他的头，他就已经是国王了
by severing heads, he'd be the king already.
他不会等德国佬
He wouldn't be waiting for the Krauts
还有他们的仆人为他献上王冠
and their servants to provide it for him.
我已经等了这么久，终于有人认清事实…
And I've been waiting for so long, for someone to finally see...
那些该死的纳粹混蛋在塞尔维亚干什么！
what these fucking Nazi bastards are doing in Serbia!
我在这里重复他们的口头禅
While I'm here, repeating their mantras,
喝他们的毒药！
drinking their poisons!
你想知道谁是老大吗？
You want to know who's in charge?
- 是谁在幕后操纵这一切? ! - 我想知道
- Who's pulling the strings?! - Yes.
但是要小心，知道之后就没有回头路了
But be careful, there's no turning back after this.
你知道谁是幕后黑手吗？
Do you know who's in charge?
医生
Doctor.
谁是医生？
And who is the doctor?
把我关在这个破地方的精神科医生
The physician who is keeping me in this dump
为了我腐败的兄弟
for my corrupt brother
还有那个同性恋日夫科维奇
and that faggot Zhivkovich.
那两个白痴
And those two morons
完全不知道那个德国仆人
have no clue what that German servant
正在秘密地为他们编造谎言
is secretly cooking up for them.
一定要这样吗？
Did it have to be this way?
真的吗? ! 我会向她解释一切的！
Did it?! I'd have explained everything to her!
是的，然后她会向她的情人解释
Yes, yes. And then she'd explain it to her lover,
穆斯塔法·戈卢比奇
Mustapha Golubich.
你真的不知道？
You had no clue?
只有上帝知道苏联人对你了解多少
God only knows what Soviets know about you.
阿瓦库莫维奇，你是圣殿骑士团的首领
Avakumovich, you are the Master of the Order,
请你有点首领的样子
please act like one.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
亲爱的…
My dear...
这会帮助你了解你父亲是什么人
This will help you understand who your father was,
以及他为什么这么做，我希望你理解
and why he did what he did. I beg you to understand.
虽然我们经常意见不合
Though we often disagreed,
但我们所做的一切都是为了你，为了你的幸福
everything we did was for you, and your happiness.
等等，歪了，你听到了吗？
Wait, it's not levelled. Do you hear?
"白兰地帮不了任何人"
BRANDY HELPED NO ONE FOUND THEIR WAY
- 你得把它拉平 - 左边？
- You have to level it. - To the left?
- 另一边，你这个傻瓜 - 但你说左边
- The other side, you dimwit. - But you said left.
左边，右边，搞什么..
Left, right, what the fuck...
你在喊什么? ! 谁在找我？
What are you yelling for?! Who's looking for me?
那两个人，我从没见过
Those two, I've never seen them.
在那儿等着
Wait there.
我的好兄弟! 你怎么来了？
My brother-in-arms! What's it with you, huh?
怎么了，兄弟？
What's up, bro?
你在主广场搭帐篷了吗？
Did you set up your tent in the main square?
我决定去看看你的这个朋友
I decided to visit this fellow of yours.
这是拉多万，也许你还记得他
This is Radovan. Maybe you remember him.
战前，他和坦科西奇在一个新兵训练营
Before the war he was in an army boot camp with Tankosich.
他怎么了？不能说话吗？
What's the matter with him? He can't talk?
他不能，他是阿尔巴尼亚人
He can't. He's an Albanian.
我何德何能有此荣幸？
To what do I owe this honour?
不是为什么事，而是为什么人
Not to what, but to whom.
致我们的指挥官，坦科耶奇公爵
To our commander, Duke Tankosich.
他是独一无二的
He was one of a kind.
当然
He sure was.
- 他死的时候你在场？ - 是的，那又怎样？
- You were there when he died? - I was, so what?
还记得那些奥地利的娘炮是多么害怕他吗？
Remember how those Austrian pussies were afraid of him?
事实上他们都不敢相信他死了
Actually, they couldn't believe he was dead,
所以他们把他挖出来
so they dug him out to make sure.
然后他们拍了一张照片，并把它发表在一份报纸上
Then they took a picture and published it in a paper.
然后把他的尸体喂狗
And they threw his body to the dogs.
我听说了
So I've heard.
你知道德国佬是怎么发现那个没有墓碑的坟墓的吗？
And have you heard how the Krauts found an unmarked grave?
- 不知道 - 好吧，听着..
- No. - Okay, listen...
有一个小镇，里面有一个药剂师
There is this town, and in it a pharmacist.
药剂师把德国佬带进了士兵的坟墓
The pharmacist took the Krauts to the soldier's grave.
德国佬为他的服务付了很高的价钱
They paid well for his service.
于是药剂师在战后去了贝尔格莱德
So the pharmacist went to Belgrade after the war
然后在那里开个店
and set up a shop there.
然后他又开了一个，一个接一个
Then he opened another one, and another.
他变得非常富有
And he became rich.
战争期间有很多这样的人
There were many people like that during the war.
的确如此
Indeed.
但是维也纳报纸上的照片，并不是只有指挥官
But the photo in the Vienna newspaper wasn't the only one.
不是吗？
No?
那个药剂师..
That pharmacist...
忍不住和死去的公爵合影
couldn't resist taking a photo of himself with the dead Duke.
所以我对自己说
So I thought to myself:
你没给我弄到那个同性恋的照片
when you couldn't get me a picture of that faggot,
但我可以给你一张
I could give you one.
拉多万
Radovan...
他就是那个药剂师
It really is him. The pharmacist.
他叫什么来着... ？
What was his name, again...?
米里奇，阿里姆皮耶 · 米里奇
Mirich, Alimpiye Mirich.
你什么意思，你不知道? ! 你怎么敢这么说！
How do you mean, you don't know?! How dare you!
他杀了国家检察官，而你却什么都不知道！
He killed the state prosecutor and you have nothing!
可能是马其顿人，可能是共产主义者! ？
Could be Macedonians, could be communists!?
你知道些什么吗? ! 听我说..
Is there anything you do know?! Listen to me...
如果你找不到是谁砍了他的头
if you don't find out who's severing people's heads,
我就把你的头砍下来，我说的够清楚了吗? ！
your heads will roll. Am I making myself clear?!
什么风把你吹来了，我亲爱的医生？
What brings you here, my dear doctor?
我有个坏消息，亲爱的将军
I have bad news, dear general.
什么事？和我们的门徒有关吗？
What? Something to do with our protégé?
不不... 一切都在掌控之中
No, no... That is under control.
好吧，这是最重要的
Ah, okay. That's the most important thing.
我洗耳恭听
I'm all ears.
这件事…
It's...
是关于我妻子的
It's about my wife.
她已经失踪好几天了
She's been gone for several days.
你为什么等了这么久才告诉我！
Why did you wait so long to tell me?!
以前也发生过
It happened before.
她... 我该怎么说呢…
She... How should I put it...
我已经怀疑很久了
You see, I've been suspecting for quite some time now,
她和这个可疑的人有一腿
that she's having an affair with this dubious character.
但她总是会回来
But she always came back.
然而，这一次，她就像人间蒸发了一样
This time, however, it's like she vanished into thin air.
这是我怀疑他们见面的地址
Here's an address where I suspect they meet.
我马上发出搜查令
I'll issue a search warrant right away.
关于这个人，你还知道些什么？
Do you know anything else about him?
没了，我怎么可能会知道？
No. How could I?
虽然有一次，在一时的愤怒中
Although once, in a fit of rage,
她确实说了些胡话，说他是个共产主义特工
she did say some nonsense that he was a communist agent,
他的名字是…
that his name was...
穆罕默德，哦不，穆斯塔法
Muhammad, no, Mustapha...
差不多吧
Something like that.
但是，将军…
But please, general...
- 请谨慎处理 - 当然
- Treat this with utmost discretion. - Of course.
会解决的，我会处理的
It will be resolved. I'll take care of it.
在你开始喝酒之前，你是个多么伟大的人啊
What a man you used to be before you started drinking.
- 给我倒酒，别废话了 - 魔鬼会带走你的
- Pour me and cut the crap. - The Devil will take you.
他很久以前就带走了我
He took me a long time ago.
你好，督察！
Hey there, inspector!
我整晚都在找你
I've been looking for you all night.
- 你也想让我操你? - 嘿！说话注意点！
- You want me to fuck you, too? - Hey, watch your mouth!
还跟我玩欲擒故纵？
Playing hard to get, eh?
老板要你去贫民窟
The boss wants you in the slum.
他是你的老板，不是我老板
He's your boss, not mine.
他是我的老板
He is my boss.
他命令我带你去那里
And he has ordered me to get you there.
我没有逮捕共产主义者，而是共产主义者逮捕我
Instead of me arresting the commies, the commies are arresting me.
- 我们生活在非常时期 - 走吧
- We live in extraordinary times. - Let's go.
白兰地帮不了任何人
BRANDY HELPED NO ONE FOUND THEIR WAY
等一下! 为我的长官演奏“德里纳进行曲”
Hold it! Play "The Drina March" for my captain.
枪放下！马上，放下！
Hands down! Right away. Hands down!
否则我将成为这里的法律和秩序！
Or I'll become the law and order here!
我知道现在接吻还太早
I know it's too early for kisses,
但在我们做完必须要做的事之前
but until we do what has to be done,
我希望你们能像兄弟一样
I want you to be like brothers.
塔纳西耶维奇，过来
Tanasiyevich, come here.
听着，他会把那个混蛋药剂师拱手相让
Listen, he'll deliver that scumbag pharmacist on a platter,
但你必须把长矛交出来
but only when you produce the spear.
- 成交? - 成交
- Deal? - Deal.
看看和我合作有多轻松，过来
See how easy it is working with me. Come on here.
你们为什么不握握手，我们可以喝一杯
Why don't you shake hands, and we can have a drink.
等我们完成工作
When we finish the job,
只要你在我背后捅刀子，我们就没事了
you'll give me the blade and you're free to go.
我不记得我们之间有什么问题
I don't remember us having any problems.
我们两个? 不可能
The two of us? Never.
把白兰地拿来
Bring that brandy.
塔尼，塔尼
Tane, Tane.
国王不是"图勒"的领袖
The prince is not the head of the "Thule" society.
我告诉过你他不是
I told you he wasn't.
你认为是米里奇？
You think it's Mirich?
米里奇是修道士，但他不是那些疯子的领袖
Mirich is the Monk, but he's not the leader of those lunatics.
他当然不是
Of course he's not.
赖斯博士说他是个正直的人
Reiss said it was a man of honour,
而米里奇只是一个暴发户
and Mirich is just another nouveau riche.
你这么聪明
When you're so clever,
为什么不告诉我谁是领袖？
why don't you tell me who the leader is?
如果不是画黑色太阳的人
If it's not the one who painted the Black Sun,
那就是那个把它挂在客厅墙上的人
then it is the one who keeps it on the wall in his living room.
阿瓦库莫维奇？
Avakumovich?
国王告诉我的
Prince has told me.
- 国王疯了 - 但不傻
- Prince is mad. - But not stupid.
仔细想想，很合理
Think about it, it fits.
我们应该告诉玛雅 · 达维多维奇
We should tell Maya Davidovich.
你以为她不知道吗？
You think she doesn't know?
苏联特务穆斯塔法·戈卢比奇是贝尔格莱德的砍头嫌疑犯
Mustapha Golubitch, the Red Bandit, Is The Beheader of Belgrade.
你雇了保镖，不相信警察了吗
You hired bodyguards, you don't trust the police.
你不也是一样
Neither do you.
- 你相信我吗？ - 作为一名警官，我相信
- Do you trust me? - As a police officer, yes.
但我不能指望你来照顾我
But I can't rely on you to take care of me.
我相信你一生的挚爱会觉得被背叛了
I'm sure the love of your life would feel betrayed.
- 你打电话叫我来就是要告诉我这个？ - 不是
- You called me to tell me that? - No.
我给你打电话是因为我想让你把那该死的矛给我
I called you because I wanted you to give me that damned spear,
就是你藏起来的那个，而人们却因此丧命
the one you're hiding, while people are getting killed for it.
我失去了一个爱我的人
I lost a man who loved me.
一个不属于别人的男人
A man who wasn't someone else's.
我失去了很多亲人
I've lost many people who were dear to me,
现在我唯一的朋友也不在了
and now the only real friend I had is gone.
然而无畏的塔纳西耶维奇督察
And the fearless Inspector Tanasiyevich
根本就不在乎
doesn't give a damn.
你以为如果我知道把那该死的长矛交给谁
Do you think I would have let people die
我会眼睁睁看着无辜的人死去吗？
because of that stupid thing if I knew whom to give it to?
你还没搞清楚谁是"图勒"的领袖？
You still haven't figured out who's the head of the Thule society?
我知道了…
I have...
但不幸的是，太晚了
but unfortunately too late.
因为你没有及时告诉我
Because you wouldn't let me know in time.
你真的认为我一直都知道？
You really think I knew this whole time?
你觉得如果我知道，我会让克里斯塔就这么死掉吗？
You think I'd let Krista die if I knew about this?!
- 但你现在知道了？ - 是的
- But you know now? - I do.
怎么知道的？
How?
阿瓦库莫维奇应该得到他想要的东西
Avakumovich should get what he's looking for.
让这些悲剧最终停止
So that these tragedies finally stop.
经过这一切，我还应该把矛交给他吗？
I should give him the lance after all this?
不用你，我会交给他的
Not you. I will give it to him.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
我在找斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇
I'm looking for Stanko Pletikosich.
哎哟，那是谁？
Ouch, who is that?
他告诉我他住在这里，斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇
He told me he lives here. Stanko. Pletikosich.
看看他！
Look at him!
多可爱的小男孩啊！
What a cute little boy!
而且彬彬有礼，不爱管闲事
And so well mannered. He's not nosy.
他长得不像你
He doesn't look like you.
幸运的是，他长得很像他的母亲
Fortunately, he looks like his mother.
否则，我永远也不会找到他
Otherwise, I never would have found him.
这么说斯坦科不住这儿？
So, Stanko doesn't live here?
这是我孙子斯坦科·普莱蒂科西奇
Here, that's Stanko Pletikosich, my grandson.
这是你的妻子，对吗？
And this is your wife, right?
当然，我有一个曾孙
Sure it is. I have a great grandson.
- 好了，爷爷，过来... - 斯坦科，这是小米沙
- Okay, grandpa, c'mon... - Stanko, meet little Misha.
米沙... 你好呀，我是斯坦科
Misha... Look at him. I'm Stanko.
来吧，到爷爷这儿来…
C'mon, come to grandpa...
我们去找一些饼干然后唱儿歌…
We'll have some cookies and sing nursery rhymes...
你知道那个著名的…
You know that famous one...
- 你找到他了？ - 是的
- You found him? - Yes.
他背上有个胎记和玛拉一样
He's got a birthmark on his back, just like Mara,
耳垂也很明显
and pronounced earlobe,
他和他妈妈长得一模一样
he's the spitting image of his mother,
我真不知道该怎么感谢你
I really don't know how to thank you,
你为我和这个孩子做了那么多
you've done so much for me and for this child.
没什么，我该走了…
It's nothing. Well, I should go now...
- 博雅纳 - 什么事？
- Boyana. - Yes?
请留下
Please stay.
我是说如果你愿意…
I mean, if you want...
如果可以的话
and if you can.
我希望你留下
I'd like you to.
玛雅
Maya.
不要再玩游戏了
No more games, please.
我什么都知道
I know everything.
我是来告诉你，我同意你向银行提出的条件
I came to tell you that I agree with your offer for the bank.
我们为什么等了这么久？
Why did we have to wait this long?
因为我不知道该找谁谈
Because I wasn't sure who was the right person to talk to.
我想知道我们的协议
I'd like to know whether our agreement
是否意味着我也要加入？
implies me joining the order?
这不是你的权利，达维多维奇女士
That's not your right, Ms. Davidovich.
这是你的职责
That's your duty.